// creating an array and passing the number, questions, options, and answers
let questions = [
    {
    numb: 1,
    question: "Kitab-I-Nauras is a collection of the poems of",
    answer: "Ibrahim Adil Shah - II",
    options: [
      "Ibrahim Adil Shah - II",
      "Ahmad =II",
      "Tajud - Din Firuz",
      "MUhammad -II"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 2,
    question: "The Cultural Development is characterised by intellectual, aestheticand spiritual attainment.s Who said the above statement",
    answer: "S.M. Fairchild",
    options: [
      "J.S. Mill",
      "S.M. Fairchild",
      "Max Weber",
      "Tansen"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 3,
    question: "Buddhist poet Asvaghosa wrote 'Buddha Charita 'in _________ language",
    answer: "Sanskrit",
    options: [
      "Prakrit",
      "Pali",
      "Urdu",
      "Sanskrit"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 4,
    question: "Choose the incorrect match: (i) Suba - sipahsalar    (ii) Sarkar - Faujdar (iii) pargana - Shiqdar  (iv) Village - Bakhshi",
    answer: "(iv) only",
    options: [
      "(i) and(ii) only",
      "(ii) only",
      "(iii) and (iv) only",
      "(iv) only"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 5,
    question: " Choose the right answer among type: Which of the 'following statements are true about Eleventh Five Yearplan of India?  (i) 'The main focus of this plan was towards faster and more inclusive growth ,  (ii) This plan stresses that benefits of development should reach all Sections of population.'   (iii) Increased rice production in the eastern part of the country",
    answer: "(i) and (ii) only",
    options: [
      "(i) only",
      " (i) and (iii) only",
      "(i) and (ii) only",
      "Answer not know"
    ]
  },
  
  {
    numb: 6,
    question: "The largest west flowing river of peninsular India is:?",
    answer: "Narmada",
    options: [
      "Mahi",
      "Sabarmati",
      "Narmada",
      "Luni"
    ]
  },

  {
    numb: 7,
    question:"Two exactly similar wires are stretched by the same load. their elasticities are in the ratio 5:3. The ratio of their elongations are",
    answer:"(A) 3:5",
    options:[
      "(A) 3:5",
      "(B) 5:3",
      "(C) 9:25",
      "(D) 25:9",
    ]
  },

  {
    numb: 8,
    question: "Human blood grouping was discovered by ?",
    answer: "Landsteiner",
    options: [
      "Landsteiner",
      "Punett",
      "Correns",
      "Muller"
    ]
  },
  
  {
    numb: 9,
    question: "In the collective model of the nucleus, the shape of nuclear core is",
    answer: "Non-spherical",
    options: [
      "Non-spherical",
      "Spherical",
      "Semi-spherical",
      "Circular"
    ]
  },

  {
    numb: 10,
    question: "Which of the following are correctly paired  (1) Kaprekar - Astrophysicist   (2) Janaki Ammal - Biologist  (3) Debashis Mukherjee - Chemistry  (4) Meghnad Saha - Mathematician ",
    answer: "2 and 3 are correct",
    options: [
      "1 and 4 are correct",
      "1 and 2 are correct",
      "2 and 4 are correct ",
      "2 and 3 are correct"
    ]
  },

  {
    numb: 11,
    question: "World Youth Skills day is celebrated on : ?",
    answer: "July,15",
    options: [
      "March,15",
      "May,15",
      "August,15",
      "July,15"
    ]
  },

  {
    numb: 12,
    question: "The first Indian male Badminton player to win a silver medal under men's singles in the world Badnginton Championship was",
    answer: "Kidambi Srikanth",
    options: [
      "Kidambi Srikanth",
      "Parpalli Kashyap",
      "Sai Praneeth",
      " Pullela Gopichand"
    ]
  },


  {
    numb: 13,
    question: "Which of the following statements are correct? (i) The nominal GS.DP growth of TN`is estimated to be 14.0 percet in 2022-23  (ii) In the TN budget estimate 2022-23, the fiscal deficit is estimated at 3.63 percent of GSDP  (iii) The outstanding debt as a percentage of GSDP is expected to be 27.76 percent in 2022-23",
    answer: "(i),(ii),and (iii)",
    options: [
      "i) only",
      "ii) only",
      "(i),(ii),and (iii)",
      "(ii) (iii)"
    ]
  },

  {
    numb: 14,
    question: "Which of the following is NOT a feature of the joint family system?",
    answer: "Individualistic identity",
    options: [
      "Authoritarian structure",
      "Familistic organisation",
      "Individualistic identity",
      "Depth of generations"
    ]
  },

  {
    numb: 15,
    question: "Tamilnadu housing board and Tamilnadu urban habitat development board were created in",
    answer: "1961 and 1970",
    options: [
      "1961 and 1970",
      "1951 and l960 `",
      "1960 and l951",
      "1970 and 1960"
    ]
  },

  {
    numb: 16,
    question: "Which of the following statement is/are true of Free Drop Back Service Janani Sishu Suraksha Kariyakaram (JSSK)?  (i)JSSK started as a pilot project in Tamil Nadu by TNHSP  (ii)Drop Back vehicle can transport mother with babies upto one year.",
    answer: "Both (i) and (ii) are true",
    options: [
      "Only (i)",
      "Only (ii)",
      "Both (i) and (ii) are true",
      "Both (i) and (ii) are false "
    ]
  },

  {
    numb: 17,
    question: "Virudhunagar Sankaralinganar, involved in an indefinite hunger strike to rename the Madras State as TamilNadu and died During ,",
    answer: "1956 October",
    options: [
      "1956 July",
      "1956 October",
      "1965 October",
      "1965 October"
    ]
  },

  {
    numb: 18,
    question: "Who was the author of the book Oppressed Hindus?",
    answer: "M.C. Rajah",
    options: [
      "M. Palaniswamy",
      "P.V. Subramanian",
      "M.C. Rajah",
      "R.Veeraiyan"
    ]
  },

  {
    numb: 19,
    question: "Which one of the following is not the achievement of Justice-Party Rule?",
    answer: "Non-Cooperation Movement",
    options: [
      "Passing Communal G.O. of 1921 and 1922",
      "Creating public service commission",
      "Non-Cooperation Movement",
      "Answer not Known"
    ]
  },

  {
    numb: 20,
    question: " Which of the following journal is not associated with Subramaniya Bharathi? .",
    answer: "New India",
    options: [
      "A New Daily",
      "Vijaya",
      "India",
      "New India"
    ]
  },

  {
    numb: 21,
    question: "Who are the ones who brave the FATE? 'Oozhaiyum uppakkam kaanpavar'- yaar?",
    answer: "Deligent people",
    options: [
      "Learned ",
      "Young people",
      "Deligent people",
      "Lazy people"
    ]
  },

  {
    numb: 22,
    question: " What Thiruvallinvar says are the qualities of an Ambassador",
    answer: "Purity, Resources, Courage",
    options: [
      "Knowledge, Origin, Education",
      "Love, Knowledge, Clarity of speech",
      "Duty, Knowing the fitting time, Knowing the place",
      "Purity, Resources, Courage"
    ]
  },

  {
    numb: 23,
    question: "What is the meaning conveyed through.the word 'extinguish ?' With.ghee extinguish fire! It will prove harder by scandal to extinguish love. ",
    answer: "Put out",
    options: [
      "Life",
      "Put out",
      "System",
      "Expertise"
    ]
  },

  {
    numb: 24,
    question: "Which moral text is exclaimed as Velaan Vedham ? ",
    answer: "Naladiyaar",
    options: [
      "Thirukkural",
      "Asarakovai",
      "Proverbs",
      "Naladiyaar"
    ]
  },

  {
    numb: 25,
    question: "In which excavation site Sir.Mortimer Wheelar used scientific and soil layer method ?",
    answer: "Arikkamedu",
    options: [
      "Pallavaram",
      "Attirampakkam",
      "Arikkamedu",
      "Kayyal"
    ]
  },

  {
    numb: 26,
    question: "When the Government of India had decided to appoint a One Man commission of Inquiry to inquire into the circumstances of the disappearance of Netaji Subhas Chandra Bose. In 1945__________'s name was recommended by the then `Chief Justice of India.",
    answer: "G.D.Khosla",
    options: [
      "Srinivasdvaradan",
      "K.K. Ghosh",
      "D.K.Roy",
      "G.D.Khosla"
    ]
  },

  {
    numb: 27,
    question: "Muhammadan Literary and `Scientific Society of Calcutta was organised by",
    answer: "Abdul Latif",
    options: [
      "Amir Ali",
      "Dudhu Miyan",
      "Abdul Latif",
      "Shariatullah"
    ]
  },

  {
    numb: 28,
    question: "The objective of Tenancy reform is",
    answer: "Abolition of Intermediaries",
    options: [
      "Abolition of Intermediaries",
      "Increase Rural Literacy",
      "Regulation ofMoriey Lenders",
      " Eradication of Rural indebtedness"
    ]
  },

  {
    numb: 29,
    question: "",
    answer: "   ",
    options: [
      "",
      "",
      "",
      ""
    ]
  },
















  // you can uncomment the below codes and make duplicate as more as you want to add question
  // but remember you need to give the numb value serialize like 1,2,3,5,6,7,8,9.....

  //   {
  //   numb: 6,
  //   question: "Your Question is Here",
  //   answer: "Correct answer of the question is here",
  //   options: [
  //     "Option 1",
  //     "option 2",
  //     "option 3",
  //     "option 4"
  //   ]
  // },
];